<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Darren Johnson on The DevOps Jedi</title>
    <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/author/darren-johnson/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Darren Johnson on The DevOps Jedi</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/author/darren-johnson/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exporting Azure Management Group Activity Logs</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2024/03/exporting-azure-management-group-activity-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2024/03/exporting-azure-management-group-activity-logs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- Summary of Article (70 Words)  &#xA;&#xA;# Table Of Contents  &#xA;&#xA;&lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;&lt;/nav&gt;  &#xA; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with Management Groups a lot recently in my day job and have really seen the benefit of being able to enforce governance by assigning RBAC roles and policies once, and have all new subscriptions inherit them. However, I soon realised there was no way in the Azure Portal or the native Azure RM Terraform provider to export the Activity Logs to a Log Analytics Workspace for use with Sentinel, so I decided to figure out a solution to this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating A Working Powershell Based Azure Function With Terraform</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2023/09/creating-a-working-powershell-based-azure-function-with-terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2023 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2023/09/creating-a-working-powershell-based-azure-function-with-terraform/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post I’ve wanted to write for a while, but was one of those side projects I’ve picked up and put down a few times due to other priorities getting in the way.  This idea came about because I wrote a PowerShell script to perform some housekeeping actions in Azure and I wanted it to run unattended on a scheduled basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Protect Secrets In Terraform Configurations</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/how-i-protect-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/how-i-protect-secrets/</guid>
      <description>I have already touched on the importance of Terraform state in a previous post, but I wanted to expand on this from a security perspective.&#xA;Let&amp;rsquo;s get this out the way now, Terraform stores secrets in its state file in plain text! There I said it.&#xA;So how do I protect against secrets being revealed that could allow an attacker to compromise my systems? Well, I use a defence in depth strategy in a number of ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Minimise Terraform Admin Effort &amp; Manage The Constant Change</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/minimise-admin-effort/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/minimise-admin-effort/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a previous post I explained why I don&amp;rsquo;t advocate the use of child modules, but I wanted to quickly explain how I keep Terraform admin overhead to a minimum when creating standard resources whilst also working with the constant rate of change that cloud brings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Use Of Terraform Child Modules</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/use-of-child-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2023 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/use-of-child-modules/</guid>
      <description>Terraform uses the construct of a module, which is defined by HashiCorp as &amp;ldquo;a set of Terraform configuration files in a single directory&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;The root module consists of resources defined in the main working directory (which I like to refer to as the &amp;rsquo;execution folder&amp;rsquo;). However, you can also call other modules to include their configuration. These are known as child modules which can be shared and reused by multiple root module configurations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Keep Terraform Simple</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/keep-it-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/keep-it-simple/</guid>
      <description>When writing a Terraform configuration, you want to keep all elements readable so whoever needs to interpret it in the future can easily understand the outcome the configuration deploys.  This is how I do it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Generate JSON With Terraform Without Using Heredoc Strings</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/generating-json-or-yaml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/generating-json-or-yaml/</guid>
      <description>This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve only recently discovered but thought it was worth sharing here.&#xA;I have a few configurations where I need to pass JSON to Terraform to process. The most used resource where I do this is azurerm_virtual_machine_extension. The example HashiCorp documentation still shows the use of Heredoc strings which is probably why I hadn&amp;rsquo;t picked up on it until now.&#xA;I recently discovered a HashiCorp article where they tell you that by using the jsonencode and yamlencode functions &amp;ldquo;Terraform can be responsible for guaranteeing valid JSON or YAML syntax&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What I Include In Every Terraform Configuration</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/what-i-include-in-every-terraform-configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/what-i-include-in-every-terraform-configuration/</guid>
      <description>I use Terraform to create and manage Azure resources, and in order to do so in a structure and consistent manner there are a number of things that I always include in every configuration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Structure Terraform Folders &amp; Apply Naming Standards</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/structure-and-naming-standards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/structure-and-naming-standards/</guid>
      <description>When I started using Terraform in 2018 the content online was mainly written from a developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective and was based on deploying resources into AWS. This was a great starting point, but the key messages in the blogs I read were all fairly consistent and seemed to align to the excellent blog series by Yevgeniy Brikman from 2016 which is well worth a read.&#xA;So, I read the series, took all the key messages onboard and started deploying resources into Azure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Lessons Learnt</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/terraform/lessons-learnt/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I explained why I chose Terraform as my IaC tool. In this series of posts I want to look at how I use Terraform and how I structure the code in a way to maximise the benefits of a declarative configuration.&#xA;Table of Contents How I Structure Terraform Folders &amp;amp; Apply Naming Standards What I Include In Every Terraform Configuration How I Keep Terraform Simple Use Of Terraform Child Modules How I Minimise Terraform Admin Effort &amp;amp; Manage The Constant Change How I Protect Secrets In Terraform Configurations </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Chose An Infrastructure As Code Tool</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2023/01/how-i-chose-an-infrastructure-as-code-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/2023/01/how-i-chose-an-infrastructure-as-code-tool/</guid>
      <description>This post looks into how, and why, I selected my current Infrastructure as Code tool of choice for my organisation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Darren Johnson and I have been working in IT for over 20 years. I currently work as a Senior Azure Platform Consultant in the UK.&#xA;Most of my career has been spent focusing on designing and delivering core data centre technologies and infrastructure from as far back as the Windows NT 4.0 days.&#xA;Having spent a number of years working as a Cloud Infrastructure Architect, in 2021 I decided to pivot and move into the DevOps space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disclaimer</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/disclaimer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/disclaimer/</guid>
      <description>The information contained within this website is accurate to the best of my knowledge at the time of writing.&#xA;Due to the rapid nature of technology change, capabilities are constantly added, updated and deprecated, so please always check the latest vendor documentation before making any changes to your own environment.&#xA;Any links provided to external websites are not an endorsement of the product or company, and are there to supplement my own articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/privacy/</guid>
      <description>I take data security and privacy very seriously, and I will not capture any Personally Identifiable Information (PII). I use the fantastic (and free) Google Analytics service to gain insights into the visitors on my site so I can tailor the content to what is proving popular.&#xA;What Data Does Google Analytics Collect? Google explains how they manage EU data and privacy here .&#xA;Key Points Google Analytics 4 does not log or store individual IP addresses.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome To My Blog</title>
      <link>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.thedevopsjedi.co.uk/welcome/</guid>
      <description>One of my goals for 2023 was to start a blog so I could keep all my notes in one place, and that would then allow me to share the content with the cloud community and hopefully benefit others who are embarking on the same journey.&#xA;I plan to capture my thoughts on technologies I use in my day job, and those I evaluate and use in my own time.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
